FAISAL NOUR

Toronto, ON | 647.309.5646 | faisalskhalifa@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn | Portfolio | Github</u>

FRONT-END DEVELOPER -

Front-end Developer and Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies CPACC with experience in designing and developing responsive and accessible user interfaces using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript. Have extensive knowledge in WCAG 2.0 accessibility standards and developing Single Page Application using React. Able to work on designing tools like Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop and InDesign), Sketch and InVision. Build strong relationships with colleagues and cross-functional teams to manage demanding timelines and achieve mutual priorities. Recently completed a Full-stack Web Development program at the University of Toronto.

SKILLS -

CORE SKILLS:

Agile Methodology | Complex Problem Solving | Front-end Frameworks | Accessibility | Web Development UI Design & Testing | Documentation

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JavaScript | jQuery | JSON | Bootstrap | React JS | Redux | GitHub | SQL | AEM | WordPress | Jira | Zephyr | Adobe Photoshop | InVision | Sketch

- RECENT PROJECTS -

GoldieMohr | Github | Website

A single page application for GoldieMohr Ltd., a construction company based in Ottawa. The company had an outdated website built by WordPress with several bugs and issues. The aim was to build a modern, easy to use, accessible and mobile responsive website using React.

- Redesigned the layout and structure of website
- Created responsive UI components and pages such as; footer, contact us, products and careers
- Performed functional testing to ensure website is accessible and compatible with various browsers

Technologies used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, SQL, EmailJS, and Node is

The Shoppies (Movie Search) | Github | Website

A single page application that allows a user to search for movies and display information using OMBD's API. Search results are displayed dynamically where users are able to nominate up to 5 movies that will be stored on browsers until they are removed from the nominated list.

- Designed and implemented simple, polished, and mobile responsive web application using React
- Used Axios for making API calls to show movie search results promptly, and LocalStorage to store nominated movies.

Technologies used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Axios, and LocalStorage

Library Management System | Github | Website

A personal web-based application to build a library management system. The aim was to build a platform that helps in handling the primary functions of libraries which involves maintaining the database.

- Designed and developed web application to store and retrieve data using RESTful API
- Designed and created a database using SQL Server to store, edit, and delete users, books, borrow and return books

Technologies used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SQL Server, RESTful API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Front-end Developer – Part time | Sinai Foundation | Toronto, Canada

2021

Recently accepted a short-term Front-end Development contract from a non-profit organization to build a new website using React.

Digital Associate | Accenture | Toronto, Canada

2019 - 2020

- Worked with agile team to analyze the current state of e-commerce integration to migrate to AEM 6.5
- Performed functional audit for six e-commerce websites to decide what features/components can be reused
- Helped Senior Managers in forms of preparing reports and presentation files
- Led research project about new technologies that could help solving complex problems

Front-end Developer | Sadda Advanced Technology | Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

2014 - 2016

- Translated UX wireframes into responsive, interactive features using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Developed and maintained websites and e-commerce sites
- Fixed bugs to optimize user experience and ensure website function and stability across devices i.e. mobile devices and tablet
- Worked with back-end developers in designing & maintaining databases using SQL Server
- Executed test cases and documented application defects in a bug tracking system JIRA

Graphic Designer | Sadda Advanced Technology | Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

2012 - 2013

- Created website designs for corporations, non-profit organizations, e-commerce, and personal
- Designed and produced multiple forms of marketing materials like banners, posters, and billboards
- Created products that are user-friendly, effective and appealing using Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator and InVision

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATE -

Master of Arts in Information Systems & Technology | York University | Toronto, Canada – Class of 2023

Full Stack Web Development Certificate | University of Toronto | Toronto, Canada – 2021

Information Technology System Analysis | IEP Bridging Program York University | Toronto, Canada – 2020

IAAP Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies CPACC – 2020

Immigration Practitioner Diploma | Canadian Society of Immigration Consultants e-Academy – 2020

AEM Business Practitioner | Adobe Certified Expert – 2019

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology & Computing | Arab Open University | Riyadh, KSA -2011